

Product Designer & Front End Developer

Melbourne, Australia



0438 950 757



Dave@davecutter.com



www.davecutter.com

DESIGN

- **Human Centred Design**
- **UI** Design
- Design Research
- **Design Systems**
- Figma, Sketch, Adobe

FRONTEND CODE

- HTML / CSS
- Javascript / Node
- React, Angular, Vue
- PHP, VbScript
- **Tailwind**
- XML, XSLT

- DAVE

PROFILE

I'm a product designer and front-end developer with 25 years experience in software product development for startup & enterprise clients. I specialise in human-centred design, intuitive UX & UI, and elegant front-end code. I also study the History & Philosophy of Science and International Politics at the University of Melbourne.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Art Processors

Product Designer / 2021 - 2024

I designed Pladia: a professional experience design app for museum and art gallery storytellers and technicians. This involved the coordination of diverse expert knowledge so I led design with collaboration. By gathering stakeholders around evolving sketches and prototypes we hashed out conflicts early while meeting product goals. As a result, the team became confident, detailoriented, and fast. Indeed, with 12 developers, I focused on rapid design & engineering engagement to get ahead of code challenges and ultimately launch Pladia - within its first year - at venues including The Sydney Opera House, the National Trust of Australia, The National Gallery of Singapore, and The Bob Dylan Center. Along the way I recruited Art Processors' expert curators, storytellers, and technicians for qualitative interviews, venue field notes, and feedback on prototypes so decisions were made on research. As a result clients reported both comfort with the UI and surprise at its power.

Mod.io

Lead Designer / 2020 - 2021

I redesigned the Mod.io home page serving two important audiences: gamers and game developers. The new home page was lauded for its clean design and funnel clarity, driving both publisher and gamer acquisition. I then redesigned Mod.io's flagship product - a gaming mod market - updating the information architecture, design system, UI, and UX to be an easier, more compelling, and more community-driven experience.

Sports Performance Tracking

Lead Designer & Frontend Developer / 2019 - 2021

I designed and FE developed SPT Bridge, an app to manage athlete tracking devices and data. Customers have been overwhelmingly appreciative of the new UX, with a 3100% increase in uploads YoY. Then, through in-depth interviews and surveys to inform our product direction, I led both the design and front-end development of SPT's flagship GameTraka, a sports-science dashboard for athletes and coaches. From team-level longitudinal views down to individual-level athletic performances, the design simplified device metrics into insightful training targets, injury warnings, and coaching guidance.



Product Designer & Front End Developer



Melbourne, Australia



0438 950 757



Dave@davecutter.com



www.davecutter.com

EDUCATION

Currently I'm pursuing a Bachelor of Arts at the University of Melbourne with dual majors: The History & Philosophy of Science and International Politics.

Previously, I studied fine arts at Emerson College in Boston from 1999 to 2002 where I co-founded the Digital Media Group, co-founded the Emerson "Communications, Politics and Law Association", and was elected Vice President of the Phi Alpha Tau Professional Communicative Arts group.

From 1998 to 1999 I studied film theory and criticism at Rhode Island College where I worked in television production and proudly earned my place as champion of the University Goldeneye N64 Tournament!



WORK EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

ESPN and The Walt Disney Company

Lead Designer & Frontend Developer / 2016 - 2019

I helped design the new ESPNfootytips native app for iOS and Android, hitting #1 in the Apple and Android App Stores for Australia, then sustaining #1 in sports throughout the AFL and NRL seasons. Though my original role was 50% email distribution, I developed software which automated that work almost entirely and eliminated scheduling problems. Internationally, I worked with ESPN HQ to design and code their first-ever AFL sites. In Australia I assisted the ESPN sales team by designing sales pitches and planning client creative integrations, and I designed all of the domestic ESPN email newsletter campaigns, improving their click-through rate by 300%.

Yahoo

Front-End Engineer & Rivals Designer / 2010 - 2013

I created and maintained sites at Yahoo Sports, including multi-league and multi-game-state responsive depth-charts, match-summaries, headers, scoreboards, favourite teams, and play-by-plays. I was part of the Yahoowide platform migration under CEO Marissa Mayer, a researcher on the Yahoo Sports User-Study initiatives, and a member of the 2012 London Olympics Event Team. (3 Billion PVs in 2 Weeks). And finally I was awarded the lead engineer and designer role for Rivals.com, the College-Sports centred fan site and chosen as technology session speaker for the 2011 and 2012 Rivals Publisher Conferences.

OTHER WORK

AdSupply / Frontend Engineer / 2013 - 2015

and Facebook games serving over 13 million players.

Working remotely from the UK for this advertising agency, I developed nextgeneration javascript ad-units and dashboards for interactive advertising.

Meteor Games / Designer & Frontend Engineer / 2007 - 2010 I was a principal hire and designed the corporate identity, managed the artto-production pipeline, and helped develop the front-end for Meteor's Web

Travelling Freelancer / Desginer & Developer / 2006 - 2007 While travelling Europe, I designed the website, packaging, and marketing materials for Dogswell Dog Treats, designed and developed an ecommerce site (increasing revenue 300%) for otaku band LeetStreet Boys, and designed an ecommerce site for humour magazine Devastator Quarterly.

Digitas / Designer, Developer & Video Editor / 2003 - 2006 I held three diverse roles at Digitas with large-audience print, web, flash, resaerch, and video projects for clients including American Express, AT&T, Celebrity Cruises, Delta, FedEx, GM, Gillette, LL Bean, and Williams-Sonoma.